all right so I'm going to show you how
to uh create
titles social media post descriptions
and YouTube
descriptions uh for podcast episodes and
and this has basically been my exact
workflow for the
last oh I would
say couple
months so we have a system prompt here
because I actually created a custom GPT
but um
um I don't know if I can I don't know if
they'll let me
um publish it for everybody yeah I guess
they
will I just have to give it a name as
far as being called
podcast uh
Creator okay so yeah so here's a GPT
called podcast Creator um you can also
do this just with like a system prompt
in custom instructions and so I'll give
you the link to the the GPT right here
um but basically the system prompt is
this it's exactly what what I use to
build this
GPT uh Your Role is to assist users in
creating podcast related content you'll
generate podcast episode titles
descriptions for YouTube and Instagram
posts based on transcripts provided by
the user emphasize creativity and SEO
expertise in crafting titles avoid any
content that would be inappropriate or
irrelevant to the podcast theme when
necessary ask for clarification okay so
I recorded a podcast episode and then I
bring it into this app called Otter AI
so I upload the video file to the
podcast in here and this is a whole
transcript of the episode which is cool
because it's like I could create any a
number of pieces of content off of this
it's a 20- minute transcript this could
become tons of pieces of content um and
I'll show you kind of a bonus prompt at
the end as far as how you could do that
but anyway any we're going to start with
this
GPT uh or you copy the system prompt
into custom instructions or in system
and basically then we just we just
paste uh that right in here we paste the
transcript and while I this isn't
exactly what I want it to
do um what I like to do is I like
to
give it a couple a little bit of
prompting as far as this goes but
basically yes it's
a it's a transcript of a podcast
episode and so what I like to do is I'll
do generate CU I never like the first
title generate me 20 possible titles for
this episode based on the transcript
above
right and that's kind of the first
prompting that we use
with this
GPT breaking the Perfection Paradox
imperfect path to some figures Beyond
oneon-one Financial
truth unconventional wisdom for for
financial
success unconventional wisdom for
success in the
coaching business okay that's what we're
going to call it because that's what the
episode is exactly so title is going to
be I kind of came up with the title um
by editing and combining a few of these
together so while that one wasn't on
this list here I came up with a title
that actually kind of fit the context
better that's a strong title so that's
one thing I would encourage you on is
don't just be BL aligned with the titles
all right generate a YouTube video
description based on
the podcast
title based on the transcript
okay and basically this is what we use
for the YouTube
description uh in this powerful episode
Jeremiah will share
this
cool
all
right now generate a podcast episode
description that can go onto Apple
podcast so this is basically a
description of the episode that can be
used uh when creating the podcast
itself so like when somebody goes to
Apple
podcast they find um this this
description generate a short one to two
sentence description based on the above
and you'll notice some podcast things
they can they allow a long form and a
short form description so I would use
this like short description in the short
form description section
there we go awesome and then
finally
generate a Facebook or Instagram post
with a
graphic to promote the new
episode write some text to go with the
graphic based on the above transcript
okay and so those prompts are basically
what I use
uh to
create the podcast episode
descriptions and we already have a
template that we use for that we got
from
canva canva.com right here is our
templating software and and they have
um you know
podcast they have a
ton of Graphics like for podcast
episodes
that's funny it's making a graphic so
this would be the text for it basically
right here new episode unconventional
wisdom for financial
success Jeremiah breaks down game
changing strategies are you ready to CH
challenge the no yep so and I and I
generally don't use
um hashtags at all so I would delete
those let's see what it creates oh
that's
funny definitely not an image I'm going
to use but that's kind of that's funny
um so anyways yep that's how we come up
with the
content then what I end up doing is I
end up going into my Google
Drive and this is where I how I uploaded
in here so what what you're you're going
to end up basically doing
this
each each
week so if I go Google Google
Drive what's up
kitty like Google Google drive right
here go Google
Drive conduit it then I find the folder
that basically has all our episodes I
create a new folder with the next
episode number podcast 2 53 we have over
253 episodes of my
podcast which is
pretty crazy and
cool then I upload the video file that I
did for the podcast
recording
here it
is well that's the one I'm doing right
now this is the podcast recording create
a Google
doc and then this is where we go into
chat chat
GPT basically I take all of the text
that's generated and I bring it all
together in that Google doc on the
Google Drive so we'll do
it's very
true I love I think this will be one of
the Milestone episodes that I give a lot
of people
to um okay so then this is going to go
with the YouTube
version so I usually put YouTube
description we paste it right
there and I mean generally like I just
that's it right there and then I have a
Jinky video person post it to YouTube
Jalan posts
it for Apple
podcast this if we put uh long
podcast
description there we go it's a great
description of what the episode is I
mean it's super super accurate and
everything
um here's a short
description so we're going to do because
they usually offer that ability short
podcast
description it's a short form
description keeps copying that photo
which is funny and then
um so social media post
text or media post description and then
that accompanies
the the
uh
file
I'll
that you can put either Link in the bio
or comment for the link or something
like that and have
a many chat or things like that do that
this kind of how I do it just Link in
link underneath and now that's ready to
go the episode is up both the video and
all the descriptions we're ready to
create it okay so that's how I use AI to
create all
the uh additional Assets in about 10
minutes for a podcast episode